Christopher Tate

Finance/Accounting Subject Matter Expert

Evans, GA 30809 christophertate74_5wv@indeedemail.com 7068322781

Budget Manager with a decade of Finance/Accounting experience. Proven high-performer in fast-paced, deadline driven environments. Great with people and numbers. Excellent written and verbal communicator with the ability to lead, coach and motivate others.

#readytowork

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Fiscal Budget Manager

CSRA REGIONAL COMMISSION - Augusta, GA August 2018 to Present

Manage budget for Area Agency on Aging (AAA) program, contracting with approximately thirty (30) subcontractors who provide an assortment of services to the 60 and over population in the Central Savannah River Area (CSRA), including nutrition, adult day care, recreation, Alzheimers care and others.

- Consistently maintain and keep expenses within \$4.7M budget while directing program reimbursements
- Implemented cost-savings initiative that will cut nutrition provider waste by 58%, reducing county government costs by \$60k, annually
- Oversee budget allocations, Accounts Payable/Receivable activity and fund balances to ensure accuracy in revenue and expense recording
- Provide direction and make recommendations to Executive leadership for maximization of government fund usage
- Perform monthly reconciliation of Small Business Administration (SBA) accounts, housing approximately \$1.6M
- Conduct on-site fiscal audits of subcontractors to assess risk and ensure Federal and State compliance

Accountant & Auditor

OFFICE OF THE CHAPTER - Augusta, GA October 2012 to August 2018

Auditor and lone staff accountant for regional bankruptcy office, administering over 10k cases in and around the Augusta, GA area.

- Administered 7,500 case audits by analyzing and interpreting legal documents to ensure compliance with government bankruptcy regulations
- Facilitated transfers of intercompany funds in excess of \$250M for disbursement to creditors

- Managed multiple company Treasury accounts
- Managed bookkeeping duties, including reconciliation of Trustee bank accounts and general ledger
- Oversaw collection efforts for over-disbursements to creditors
- Created and delivered training for newly-hired employees

Project Accountant

The Shaw Group Inc - Aiken, SC August 2010 to October 2012

Accounts Payable Lead for multi-billion dollar federal Mixed-Oxide (MOX) project, operated by Department of Energy (DOE).

- Administered over \$1B in payments to foreign and domestic subcontractors in two-year span
- \bullet Led peer-review effort that reduced invoice errors by 70% and consistently exceeded billing forecasts by 10% 15%
- Spearheaded payment process that increased efficiencies and reduced subcontractor wait time by 80% of contract terms
- Collaborated with executive leadership, vendors and subcontract administrators to ensure timely DOE billing and payment delivery
- Performed bi-weekly account reconciliation and prepared month-end general ledger reports to record revenue and expenditures
- Supervised employee workflow and trained newly-hired employees
- Performed intercompany audits to ensure adherence to company policies

Education

Master of Science in Business Administration

Augusta State University - Augusta, GA
December 2009

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

North Greenville University Tigerville - Tigerville, SC December 2007

Skills

- Account Reconciliation Auditing Billing Bookkeeping Budget Management Client Relations Communication Compliance/Regulations Financial Analysis Fiscal Reporting Forecasting GAAP Grant Funding Leadership Manufacturing Non-Profit Organizations Process Improvement Risk Analysis Strategic Planning Treasury Management
- Accufund
- Costpoint
- Google Suite
- Microsoft Excel (macros, pivot tables, etc.)
- Passport
- QuickBooks
- SharePoint
- General Ledger Accounting

- · Bank Reconciliation
- General Ledger Reconciliation
- · Accounts Payable
- Journal Entries
- Internal Audits
- · Accounts Receivable
- · Business Analysis
- Financial Statement Preparation
- · Account Reconciliation
- Accounting
- Financial Analysis
- GAAP

Assessments

Project Timeline Management — Expert

November 2019

Prioritizing and allocating time to effectively achieve project deliverables.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share_to_profile/8be1a1fc18c4b78d52e4f001ddfb688aeed53dc074545cb7

Basic Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Expert

September 2019

Measures a candidate's knowledge of basic Microsoft Excel techniques, including sorting, formatting, and filtering of columns or rows.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/attempts/ca17899c1981d323229deb085c0ff1b3eed53dc074545cb7

Problem Solving — Proficient

November 2019

Analyzing relevant information when solving problems.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_to_profile/da67d53bd63a66ea179153eda75c4e25eed53dc074545cb7

Business Math — Expert

January 2020

Using basic math to solve problems in a business context.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

attempts/9177d4849aa10263feef9e387264d89feed53dc074545cb7

Project Management Skills: Budgeting — Highly Proficient

February 2020

Managing project budgets by appropriately allocating and monitoring financial resources.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/1ce5f8603f4bdb99939f0fdd978b3427eed53dc074545cb7

Intermediate Spreadsheet Proficiency with Microsoft Excel — Expert

September 2019

Measures a candidate's knowledge of intermediate Microsoft Excel techniques including effectively writing and applying conditional formulas.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/attempts/d32aa4e55a520dcaa9497cc0947fbc9feed53dc074545cb7

Data Entry Clerk — Highly Proficient

February 2020

Maintaining data integrity by detecting errors. Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

attempts/6acc695d9d9f531a4a636ba1d3712f03eed53dc074545cb7

Supervisory Skills: Interpersonal Skills — Highly Proficient

February 2020

Fostering a collaborative environment and conducting difficult conversations.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_to_profile/655ec3c94a47fcb28f9b59bc7a907d9a

Verbal Communication — Expert

February 2020

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/5f570cb22e4e5328d58709616067248aeed53dc074545cb7

Work Style: Conscientiousness — Expert

March 2020

Tendency to be well-organized, rule-abiding, and hard-working.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/attempts/e4164ba4fb2255ff9f4e8b77af32f02b

Typing — Highly Proficient

January 2020

Transcribing text using a standard keyboard.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

attempts/309e6af8bcb8230c793f9a84e1f27505eed53dc074545cb7

Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Highly Proficient

March 2020

Excel knowledge including common tools, PivotTables, conditional & nested formulas, and custom visuals.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

attempts/81bf767dbaae6f166e69cf76c6773db7eed53dc074545cb7

Work Motivation — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Level of motivation and discipline applied toward work

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

attempts/19d0fa7ce6b9ce9b710dafc4c20779dfeed53dc074545cb7

Filing & Organization — Expert

February 2020

Arranging and managing information or materials using a set of rules.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/attempts/ad597b28dbcd52cac0b99e246854b763eed53dc074545cb7

Data Entry — Highly Proficient

January 2020

Entering data quickly and accurately.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/attempts/b2ee19cb815fe01d42ff30c2e681785ceed53dc074545cb7

Attention to Detail — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/ share to profile/2ed33b0e007df269c81faac3879f6aaa

Supervisory Skills: Motivating & Assessing Employees — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Motivating others to achieve objectives and identifying improvements or corrective actions.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

 $\underline{attempts/4fca861045002419e130983382403b23eed53dc074545cb7}$

Analyzing Data — Highly Proficient

May 2020

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/ share to profile/71a84c34ca47dc7ce3e463e965db37a8

Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Highly Proficient

March 2020

Excel knowledge including common tools, PivotTables, conditional & nested formulas, and custom visuals.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

<u>attempts/81bf767dbaae6f166e69cf76c6773db7eed53dc074545cb7</u>

Emotional Competence — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Managing one's own emotions and understanding those of others.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

attempts/0d5936e7aa017bfa05eb9de6b3927772eed53dc074545cb7

Attention to Detail — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_to_profile/e2838b2ef160db4996997f9a63a96811eed53dc074545cb7

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.